Previously on
The Big Bang Theory...
We now pronounce you
husband and wife!
I love this part!
Me, too!
I have strongly mixed feelings!
So, Howard's really
in space, huh?
Mm-hmm, International
Space Station.
250 miles that way.
Right now, Howard's
staring down at our planet
like a tiny Jewish Greek god.
Zeusowitz.
I must admit,
I can't help
but feel a twinge of envy.
He can look out the window and
see the majesty of the universe
unfolding before his eyes.
His dim, uncomprehending eyes.
It's like a cat
in an airport carrying case.
You know, it's not exactly
glamorous up there.
The water that
the astronauts drink
is made from each other's
recycled urine.
Must be nice.
Nobody wants anything
that comes out of me.
I wonder what he's
doing right this very second.
Mm, conducting experiments
in zero gravity.
Peering through his telescope
at the birth of the cosmos.
Whatever it is, we know his
life will never be the same.
Howard! Can you hear me?!
I can hear you
without the phone!
Don't be snippy.
I'm just excited to talk
to my baby!
I'm excited to talk to you, too.
So, what's this mishegas
about you moving out
to go live with
the little Polish girl?!
How about calling her my wife?
Wives don't take boys
from their mothers.
They do.
That's why we marry them!
I just hope I'm not dead
from a broken heart
before you get back.
Ma, please. Everyone from NASA
is listening to this phone call.
Good. They should know
what a horrible son you are!
Okay, Ma, great talking to you!
Gotta go!
Well... space is ruined.
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool ♪
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall ♪
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪
♪ The Big Bang Theory 6x01 ♪
The Date Night Variable
Original Air Date on September 27, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
This is so exciting.
Soon, my upper lip will
be the same fake blonde
as my beautiful
best friend.
Hey, this is
my natural hair color.
Now.
So, does Sheldon have
anything special
planned for you
tomorrow night?
Oh, yes. According to the
Relationship Agreement,
on the anniversary
of our first date,
he must take me to a nice
dinner, ask about my day
and engage in casual
physical contact
that a disinterested onlooker
might mistake for intimacy.
That's hot.
You kids better use protection.
How long does
this stay on?
Just a couple of minutes.
You've really never
done this before?
Once in high school,
but I dozed off
and woke up with second-degree
chemical burns on my face.
Oh, my gosh,
that's awful.
The other kids
make fun of you?
No, I had a cover story;
I told everyone it was herpes.
So, how's everything going
with you and Leonard?
I don't know,
it's still kind of weird.
We haven't really recovered
since he proposed to me
in the middle of sex.
Oh. Boo-hoo.
If Sheldon proposed
to me during sex,
my ovaries would grab on to him
and never let go.
Leonard, where do you stand
on the anthropic principle?
Interesting question. On the
one hand, I always thought...
You don't even know
what it is, do you?
The anthropic principle states
that if we wish to explain
why our universe exists
the way it does,
the answer is that
it must have qualities
that allow intelligent
creatures to arise
who are capable of
asking the question.
As I am doing
so eloquently right now.
I know what
the anthropic principle is.
Of course.
I just explained it to you.
Now, where do you
stand on it?
Where do you stand on it?
Strongly pro.
Then I believe that God
created the world in six days,
and on the seventh,
he made you to annoy me.
Hey, guys.
Hey.
Yeah, wait, Raj,
where do you stand
on the anthropic
principle?
I'm all for it.
Attaboy!
Well, hang on.
Why do you believe
that he knows
what it is and I don't?
Oh, Leonard.
Let's not take a saw
to the branch
we're sitting on, shall we?
Hey, uh,
if you guys
are free tonight, I heard about
a spa where you soak your feet
in a pool full of little fish
that eat all the dead skin
right off them.
I don't need
to tell you,
in Los Angeles, sandal
season is year round.
Actually, I'm hanging
out with Penny.
Oh, okay. Sounds like
it's me and you, Sheldon.
How about we sic some guppies
on those puppies?
As I've stated before
on numerous occasions,
the only sea creature I would
even consider being eaten by
is the Kraken, because
the last words I would hear are:
"Release the Kraken."
That never gets old.
"Release the Kraken!"
Oh, chills.
Besides, I'm having
dinner with Amy.
Oh, okay. I'll just go home
and be alone.
W-Which is cool.
I eat alone, I sleep alone,
I cry alone, so...
Cool.
Darn. If you weren't busy,
I'd ask you to join us.
Really? I can
come? Thanks!
Sheldon, are you sure
you want to be bringing Raj
on your date night
with Amy?
Oh, absolutely.
I have a contractual obligation
to provide Amy with conversation
and casual
physical contact,
but nowhere is it specified
that I can't outsource that
to an Indian.
Howie?
Hey, there's my beautiful bride!
Can you see me?
I can.
How are you?
I'm amazing.
I mean, this is
even better than I dreamed.
I look out the window, and...
it's all so unbelievable.
Good for you.
I just had a seemingly endless
dinner with your mom.
Oh, yeah? That's nice.
It was. Until I found out
you never told her
we're not gonna live with her.
Let's talk about that
for a minute.
Hey, look, this pen is floating.
How crazy is that?
You said you told her,
but you never did!
Okay, okay, I know
you're upset, but...
let me share something
I've learned since I got here.
You realize
how small your problems are
when you're looking down
on them from space.
Now, come on, that's got
to make you feel better.
How clear is the image
of me on that screen?
Pretty clear.
Do I look like I feel better?
I mean, it's not, like,
HD quality.
Listen, mister, you're
gonna talk to your mother
and you're gonna fix this,
or that thing I said
I was gonna do to you
the minute you got home,
you can do to yourself.
Like he's been
doing since he got here.
Sheldon, this place
is so romantic.
Oh, I'm glad you like it.
Raj picked it out.
Well, when you see him,
tell him I say thank you.
Tell him yourself.
Yoo-hoo!
Over here!
I don't understand.
What's he doing here?
I invited him.
On our date?
Sheldon, that's not okay.
Yes, it is.
There's a loophole
in the Relationship Agreement.
You found a loophole?
Sorry I started without you.
I'm a little nervous.
It's been a long time
since I've been on a date.
I can't believe I bleached
my mustache for this.
You should go
to my girl.
She'll knock out
those sideburns for free.
Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
You know, Amy,
I don't even think
you and I have had
a real conversation.
Let's use tonight to get to know
each other a little better.
You start.
Go home.
I don't understand.
Sheldon, how could you do this?
It's our second anniversary.
It's your anniversary?!
Oh, my God, I had no idea.
Amy, please,
let me make this right.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
Waiter?
A bottle of champagne
and three glasses.
Oh, boy,
isn't this romantic?
Oh, I hope that's
a rhetorical question,
because I have no clue.
This is great.
What's the occasion?
No occasion. You know,
things have been
a little weird between us,
so I wanted to throw together
a fun night
just for you.
That is so sweet.
I got all your favorites.
Beer, wings, sliders.
We can watch the
football game.
I even painted my stomach.
"Go sports"?
Well...
in case you were in
the mood for baseball,
I didn't want to
look ridiculous.
This is awesome.
I love it!
Good, I'm glad.
Gosh, I worked
my ass off today.
This is exactly
what I needed.
Great. Just relax and enjoy.
Tonight is all about you.
Ah, thank you!
So, where exactly are we
in this relationship?
Oh, come on!
I just told you
I had a hard day.
You're right, I'm sorry.
Let's watch the game.
Great.
I just know the longer
we wait to talk about it,
the weirder it gets.
Sweetie, can I just be
the girl tonight?
Absolutely.
You're the girl, I'm the guy.
Now, you watch
your football game
while I make you a
little plate here.
Thank you!
Oh, I'll get it.
Go sports!
Hello-lo-lo.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were out
th Sheldon and Amy.
I was, but it's
their anniversary
and I didn't want
to be a third wheel,
so I figured I'd come over here
and hang out with you
and Penny on your date.
Well, it's not really
a great time.
Penny and I have some things
we need to talk about.
No, we don't!
Come on in!
Sweet!
I can't believe
I shaved my stomach for this.
Hey, Froot Loops.
You got a phone call.
Who is it?
A woman who says
she's your mother
but sounds like
your father.
Hey, Ma.
You know, we could
see each other
if you turn on the computer.
I'm not going near
that fakakta thing.
I'll catch a computer virus!
You can't catch
a computer virus.
Oh, so now you're an astronaut
and a doctor?
What do you want, Ma?
Your wife says you have
something important to tell me.
Okay, here it is.
Bernadette and I are starting
a life together and...
Oh, God!
You are gonna leave me!
Ma...
It's okay.
Your father left me,
you left me--
I guess I'm just the kind
of person people like to leave.
It's not... definite.
I'll talk to Bernadette.
Don't bother.
I'll just go sit in a hole
in the ground
so I'm no trouble when I die.
Stop it, Ma.
I'm sure I can get
Bernie to come around.
I knew it!
I knew she was behind this!
You listen to me,
if you want to be a man,
you can't let a woman
tell you what to do!
Okay,
okay.
I can't believe these people
won the Cold War.
Now, can we please
change the subject?
Fine.
Explain why
you've been gone so long
and I haven't gotten
a single letter.
Not even a lousy postcard!
You know, I'm growing to like
American football.
Yeah, it's fun, isn't it?
Well...
it's not the balls-to-the-wall
action of badminton or cricket,
but hey...
what is?
All right, who's ready
for another beer?
I'm good.
No, thank you.
Girls.
I am having
the nicest time.
You guys are like
family to me.
You know that, right?
That's great.
Get out.
What? Why?
Penny and I have some issues
we need to talk about.
Oh...
pish on your issues!
You guys are fine.
Yes, you hit some bumps
along the way.
I mean, Penny,
you've always known how this man
has felt about you,
but you made him
grovel for affection.
Okay, hold on...
Now, don't blame yourself.
He was a groveler from way back.
But the point is,
the two of you got past it.
And, Leonard,
you go and propose
to this poor girl
in the middle of sex?
That was some weak tea, dude.
Some people might
say it was romantic.
Yeah, no.
But yet, here you two are,
still together.
And that's even after you and I
had our crazy naked night.
Okay...
That's enough.
I'm just saying
that after everything
you've been through,
you get to look
into each other's eyes
and say "I love you."
And that's beautiful.
Actually, to this day,
she's never really said it.
Oh, Penny!
That's ridiculous!
You know you love him!
You look him in the eyes
and you say it.
Raj...
Oh, come on,
you know you want to say it.
Say it.
Say you love him.
Say it!
I really thought
she would say it.
Have I ever told you you're
like a sexy praying mantis?
Every time you drink alcohol.
You know what's wonderful
about the praying mantis?
They devour their mate.
Your point being?
Dessert is served.
I just had cobbler.
You know what?
I'm done with this.
W-Where are
you going?
I'm leaving.
You can't leave.
I need you.
You do?
Yes.
You're my ride.
Sheldon, you either say
something meaningful
and from the heart,
or you and I are done.
All right.
Please.
Amy...
when I look in your eyes
and you're looking
back in mine,
everything feels
not quite normal,
because I feel
stronger and weaker
at the same time.
I feel excited and,
at the same time, terrified.
The truth is,
I don't know
what I feel, except...
I know what kind of man
I want to be.
Sheldon...
that was beautiful.
I should hope so.
That's from the first
Spider-Man movie.
I'll take it.
Good.
Now, I assume
we're splitting the check?
Hey, Stuart.
Oh, hey. I was actually
just about to close up.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll leave.
No, no. It's
okay. Hang out.
You sure?
Yeah, you're
my first customer today.
All right. Great.
I'm, uh, having a nightcap.
You want to join me?
What are you drinking?
Coffee liqueur
in a Chewbacca mug.
I call it a sad-tini.
Perfect for the night
I'm having. Thank you.
Hmm. Nice not
to drink alone.
Amen to that.
Sometimes I pour
a little chardonnay
into my dog's water bowl.
You're kidding.
She's kind of a mean drunk,
but what are you gonna do?
Cheers.
A little music?
Sure.
Mmm. Bossa nova.
You listen to that with
your hips as well as your ears.
Mmm.
Oh.
Something about...
Latin music just
makes me feel like
I'm on a white sand beach
in Rio.
Yeah.
The sun, the waves,
the beautiful bodies,
tanned and glistening
with sweat.
I should go.
Yeah.
Uh, thank you
for the drink.
No problem.
Hey, Stuart.
Yeah?
Do you want to...
hang out tomorrow night,
maybe grab a bite to eat
or catch a late movie?
Yeah, I-I'd like to,
but I'm a little tight on funds.
No problem. My treat.
I'll swing by after work.
Okay.
I could do worse.
Aw, that's such
good news, Howie.
Thank you for telling her.
Hey, I'm a grown man;
I'm gonna live with my wife.
My mother's just gonna have
to learn to make do on her own.
Was she upset?
Who can tell?
She yells everything.
She might have been upset.
She might have been hungry.
Thanks for fixing it.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Sweet dreams.
I'll talk to you tomorrow?
Good night, Rocket Man.
To infinity and beyond, baby.
Loops.
You realize you just
lied your ass off
to your wife
and your mother.
I know.
What are you gonna do
when you get back to Earth?
Oh, I'm never going back.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org